Guide to the Stanford University Objects Collection SC1048
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Objects
  - Leather postcards (2): "Rah Rah Rah, Stanford", ARCH-AM-00-061 (Box 1)
    00-061.1 red leather with white S; postmarked 1903 00-061.2 brown leather with images of girl holding pennant; postmarked 1903
  - Leather postcards(12 of street scenes and athletics- 1907), sent to Myrtle Mabbott, ARCH-AM-1982-14 (Box 1)
  - Leland Stanford, Jr. 24X16cm image, 43X36cm frame. Purple velvet with gold corners. Tinted image on cerameic. Signed by Fr. Jill Dresden., ARCH-AM-00-124 (Box 1)
  - Leland Stanford's pen and leather booklet for wiping it (entitled "Extracts from the pen of Senator Stanford"), ARCH-AM-2005-003 (Box 1)
    2005-003.1 pen 2005-003.2 leather booklet
  - Letter box that held correspondence of ASSU president Bruce Jessup, ARCH-AM-1995-17 (Box 1)
  - Letter form Board of Trustees to Jane L. Stanford, (when trustees assume active care; states principals; no frame; 39x53 cm., June 5th, 1903; ARCH-AM-00-082 (Box 1)
  - Letter opener (5.25 in. long, silver) with University seal on handle. Still on original gift card; signed on reverse "From Garrett Elmore June 20, 1927", ARCH-AM-2009-002 (Box 1)
  - Letter sweater, Driggs recorded as swimmer (went to Olympics in '28). red knit with white S., ARCH-AM-1980-16 (Box 1)
  - Letterman's sweater of Tyler F. Woodward, class of 1924 - gold sweater with red S and 3 red stars, ARCH-AM-2005-035 (Box 1)
  - Library Perforator, 28x13x15 cm. heavy black metal, "Library Leland Stanford University", circa 1892; ARCH-AM-00-101 (Box 1)
  - License plate holder "All Right Now!" "Stanford '80" - memento from 25th reunion of the Class of 1980 held in Fall of 2005., ARCH-AM-2005-037 (Box 1)
  - Lithograph- Horse "Palo Alto", ARCH-AM-00-358 (Box 1)
  - Lockets, ARCH-AM-00-216 (Box 1)
    00-216.1 Locket, gold, 1.5x1cm, 1939 Senior Ball. 00-216.2 Locket, gold, 1.5x1cm, 1939 Senior Ball. 00-216.3 Locket, gold, 1.5x1cm, 1939 Senior Ball. 00-216.4 Locket, gold, 1.5x1cm, 1939 Senior Ball.
  - Logo in metal: "VA varian", ARCH-AM-1999-009 (Box 1)
  - Loose issues of early Daily Palo Alto for possible exhibit use, 1898-1916., ARCH-AM-2003-003 (Box 1)
    Vol. 8-9: Sept. 2, 1898, Sept. 22, 1898, Mar. 1, 1899, Mar. 21, 1899, Mar. 24, 1899 Vol. 16: Jan. 12 - May 30, 1900 [including commencement issue] Vol. 17: Sept. - Dec. 1900 Vol. 27-36: 1905: Sept. 22, Oct. 5, Oct. 16, Oct. 18-20, Oct. 25 1907: Sept. 10-11 1908: Nov. 6, Nov. 10 1909: Jan. 5-6, Mar. 25 1910: Jan. 18-20, Apr. 28 Vol. 30 Jan. 8 - May 10, 1907. Missing issues: #8 Jan. 17, #36-37 Feb. 27-28; #66 Apr. 13 Vol. 35 Aug. 1909 - Dec. 9, 1909 [bound without boards]. Missing issues: #2-3 Sept. 1-2; #66 Dec. 2 Vol. 38-48: 1911: Mar. 9, Oct. 2 [20th anniversary] 1912: Mar. 19, Sept. 3 1913: Oct. 1 [Branner's installation as president] 1914: Jan. 23, Feb. 11, Feb. 16-17, Mar. 9, Oct. 6 1915: Sept. 1 1916: May 2 [D. S. Jordan retires]
  - Leland Stanford death memorial: white satin with fringe, on metal rod. "In Memory of Leland", ARCH-AM-1995-30 (Box 1)
  - LSJU Fire Dept. Helmet, used in Encina Hall fire., circa 1969-1970; ARCH-AM-1988-001 (Box 1)
  - Magnet: [class of ] 80 / Stanford Reunion Homecoming / [2 inch square], October 19-22, 2000; ARCH-AM-2007-004 (Box 1)
  - Mandolin and case. Case inscriptions (list of concerts) start in 1900 and end in 1902. Label inside mandolin: the New Washburn model 1897. Gourd-shaped body, mother of pearl inlay on neck. No strings; body badly cracked., ARCH-AM-2007-008 (Box 1)
  - Mandolin case, used by member of Mandolin club, ARCH-AM-00-059 (Box 1)
  - Map, framed & colored. Stanford Campus, by Della Taylor, 1938; ARCH-AM-00-352 (Box 1)
  - Map, framed & colored. Stanford University, by Ed Farmer, 1934; ARCH-AM-00-353 (Box 1)
  - Map, Lands of Stanford, lithograph, Hermann Brothers., 1908; ARCH-AM-00-354 (Box 1)
  - Marble from Art Museum; Plaster pieces showing original wall colors from Art Gallery; Wallpaper (fabric) from Art Gallery, ARCH-AM-2005-029 (Box 1)
  - Marble sculpture by William Couper of Jane L. Stanford's hands, ARCH-AM-00-023 (Box 1)
  - Marble square with image of new wing of Iris & B. Gerald Cantor Center for Visual Arts with "thank you January 24, 1999", ARCH-AM-2000-021 (Box 1)
  - Marshall ribbons from Commencement 2002 (2), ARCH-AM-2002-26 (Box 1)
  - master's hood, ARCH-AM-1982-10 (Box 1)
  - Masters hood, 1928; ARCH-AM-1982-11 (Box 1)
  - Masters hood, red inside, white border. 73x 47 cm., ARCH-AM-1984-43 (Box 1)
  - Match books, ARCH-AM-1984-52 (Box 1)
    1. 45th class reunion June 3, 1972. 1927-1972 2. 1869 East-West R.R.
  - Matchbook issued by Stanford Bank with slogan "Follow Stanford Sports" and image of Indian head & headress on front and 1971 football schedule inside, ARCH-AM-2003-005 (Box 1)
  - Mayfield Curtain. 22 advertisements of local businesses painted in oils by Otto Schroeder. The article states it is 24x12, but it is apparently 8x18 feet., ARCH-AM-2006-009 (Box 1)
  - Medal awarded to H. T. Woodward, for 100 yard run, AAU, 1892; ARCH-AM-00-056 (Box 1)
  - Medal awarded to LSJU by Ca. State Agric Society, for Jr. champion holstein bull. 1.75" diameter; silver metal, 1904; ARCH-AM-00-025 (Box 1)
  - Medal awarded to LSJU by Ca. State Agric Society, for Grand champion holstein-fresian bull. 1.75" diameter; yellow metal, 1911; ARCH-AM-00-026 (Box 1)
  - Medal in Blue Box. Box= 10x10x3cm. Medal= 7cm diam., re B & O Railroad., ARCH-AM-00-217 (Box 1)
  - Medal in box, 7 cm diam. Awarded to E.P. Cubberly, Butler Silver Medal., 1915; ARCH-AM-00-243 (Box 1)
  - Medal in box. Medal 7cm diam. Awarded to E.P. Cubberly by Columbia Univ. N.Y.C., 1933; ARCH-AM-00-242 (Box 1)
  - Medal in gray box. Medal 7.5cm diam. World's Columbian Exposition; given to John C. Branner., ARCH-AM-00-253 (Box 1)
  - Medal in red box. 9x9x1 cm box, Louisiana Purchase Exhibition., ARCH-AM-00-212 (Box 1)
  - Medal in red box. Box = 9x9x1cm, Universal Exposition, St. Louis. Awarded to J.C. Branner., 1904; ARCH-AM-00-213 (Box 1)
  - Medal in red box. Medal = 4cm, Panama Pacific International Expo. To Ellwood P. Cubberly. (Box 6x1 cm), 1915; ARCH-AM-00-241 (Box 1)
  - Medal on ribbon & Place Card of Leland Stanford, at Presidential Inagural (Harrison)., 1889; ARCH-AM-00-206 (Box 1)
  - Medal on ribbon, 2.8cm diam. "Romma Commvnis Patris," in brown case 6x8x1 cm., ARCH-AM-00-219 (Box 1)
  - Medal, 6x5cm. Profile of Napolean (?), ARCH-AM-00-214 (Box 1)
  - Medal, J. H. Meyer, Le Exposition de Paris, 4.5 cm, ARCH-AM-1984-48 (Box 1)
  - Medal: 7.5cm. Daniel Webster in case., ARCH-AM-00-205 (Box 1)
  - Medal: 7x4 cm. 11 September, SACRA Saecvlaria Celebrat, ARCH-AM-00-204 (Box 1)
  - Medals awarded to Quate, ARCH-AM-2004-002 (Box 1)
    2004-002.1 IEEE Third Mellenium Medal, 2000 2004-002.2 IEEE Medal of Honor 1988 2004-002.3 National Medal of Science, 1992 2004-002.4 National Medal of Technology 2004-002.5 Aspen Highlands Silver Nastar
  - Medals received by Prof. S. P. Timoshenko (13 awards; 16 medals), 1911-1962; ARCH-AM-1979-02 (Box 1)
    .1 Jourawski medal (1911) .2 Worcester Reed Warner medal (1935) (2 medals) .3 Benjamin Garver Lamme medal (1939) (2medals) .4 Louis Edward Levy medal (1944) .5 James Watt International medal (1947) (2 medals) .6 Trasenster medal (1948) .7 Elliott Cresson medal (1958) .8 James Alfred Ewing medal (1962) .9 R.F. - O. A.; .10 University of Zabreb (1969?) .11 Academie des Sciences (1966?) .12 National Academy of Scinces of the U.S. (1963) .13 Leonhardo Eulero Academia Scientiarum (1957)
  - Megaphone. 23x48 cm diam. Stanford Nebraska Rose Bowl. Red on top, white on bottom., 1941; ARCH-AM-00-191 (Box 1)
  - Megaphone. 23 x 13 cm diameter. "Charter House 'Desmond's' Five Los Angeles Stores". Red on top, white on bottom., undated; ARCH-AM-2015-008 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, circa 1940s-1990s; Accession ARCH-AM-2017-002
    - Sweaters, pins, decal (Box 1)
      AM-2017-002.01 White Block S Sweater; AM-2017-002.02 Red Block S Sweater; AM-2017-002.03 Lil Injun decal; AM-2017-002.04 45 Stanford 60th Reunion pin; AM-2017-002.05 Stanford Travel/Study pin, 1993; AM-2017-002.06 Stanford Travel/Study pin, 1996; AM-2017-002.07 “To Hell with ’51” pin, 1996; AM-2017-002.08 Class of ’50 “Non-Reunion”, November 16, 1990
    - Pennants (Box 2)
      AM-2017-002.09 White Stanford 45 penants (2); AM-2017-002.10 Red Stanford pennant with seal; AM-2017-002.11 Red Stanford Indians Rose Bowl pennant
  - Memorabilia - award and charm bracelet, ARCH-AM-1995-11 (Box 1)
    1. "Gold Spike" awarded to Fred Glover in honor of fundraising activities, 1974 2.Charm bracelet Fred made for his wife: boxing gloves, PBK pin, boxing medals
  - Memorabilia - buttons, pins, pennants, decal, sweaters, Accession ARCH-AM-2017-002 (Box 1, Box 2)
    Box 1: ARCH-AM-2017-002.01 White Block S Sweater; ARCH-AM-2017-002.02 Red Block S Sweater; ARCH-AM-2017-002.03 Lil Injun decal; ARCH-AM-2017-002.04 45 Stanford 60th Reunion pin; ARCH-AM-2017-002.05 Stanford Travel/Study pin, 1993; ARCH-AM-2017-002.06 Stanford Travel/Study pin, 1996; ARCH-AM-2017-002.07 “To Hell with ’51” pin, 1996; ARCH-AM-2017-002.08 Class of ’50 “Non-Reunion”, November 16, 1990 Box 2: ARCH-AM-2017-002.09 White Stanford 45 penants (2); ARCH-AM-2017-002.10 Red Stanford pennant with seal; ARCH-AM-2017-002.11 Red Stanford Indians Rose Bowl pennant
  - Memorabilia - dance card and box, circa 1903; ARCH-AM-1995-14 (Box 1)
    1. Dance card/program for junior prom 3/27/1903 in shape of plug ugly hat (3 dimensional) 2. box that holds photographs of Stanford
  - Memorabilia - dance cards from Stanford C.S.C.'s Second Annual Coronation Ball. Red with white cord.1948(2), t-shirts (2), and Stanford dividex pages., 1948-1949; ARCH-AM-2017-015 (Box 1)
    ARCH-AM-2017-015.01 Dance card (copy 1); ARCH-AM-2017-015.02 Dance Card (copy 2); White shirt with Lil Injun in red ARCH-AM-2017-015.03; Red long sleeved shirt with Indian in white ARCH-AM-2017-015.04; 1948-1949 Stanford Dividex pages ARCH-AM-2017-015.05
  - Memorabilia - football, trophies, awards, and his hat, ARCH-AM-1994-04 (Box 1)
    1. Football signed by various S.U. coaches 2. 1938 trophy: "Area Contest - won by Fred Glover, 2/28/38" 3. 1953 loving cup, Stanford '33 - 20th reunion: Baldest 4. Award to Glover from Delta Tau Delta 5. 2 medals 6. Stanford Association Award, 1989 7. Centennial Award 1991 8. Fred's last hat
  - Memorabilia - tie and pennant, ARCH-AM-1993-03 (Box 1)
    1. Red tie with S. Indian painted on it 2. Red felt STANFORD pennant
  - Memorabilia from Farewell dinner to General Porfirio Diaz on his departure from New York, Union League Club, 24 April 1883 - notice of dinner and guest list (includes Hon. Leland Stanford) printed on silk, with fringed edges. Notice has painted vignettes., ARCH-AM-2004-017 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia from Muir and Burbank houses: sweatshirt with image of Sterling on back and "faculty associate" on front, awarded to graduating senior 1959; 3 mugs with image of Bufano's "Penguin" statue that used to sit between Muir and Burbank houses. See collection file for further notes, ARCH-AM-2002-32 (Box 1)
    2002-32.1 Sweatshirt 2002-32.2 Mug 2002-32.3 Mug 2002-32.4 Mug
  - Memorabilia from presidential inauguration of Benjamin Harrison 1889, ARCH-AM-2005-002 (Box 1)
    2005-002.1 Inaugural ball program 2005-002.2 Inaugural ball program 2005-002.3 Souvenir menu 2005-002.4 image of B. Harrison on unknown surface 2005-002.5 image of Mrs. Harrison on unknown surface
  - Memorabilia: Buttons, reunion ID tags, Class of '51 address stamps, red feather, paper flag of Mexico, ARCH-AM-2007-021 (Box 1)
    2007-021.1 Button: Once an Indian Always an Indian 2007-021.2 Button: red S 2007-021.3 Button: red S with laurel leaves on either side 2007-021.4 Button: Stanford '51 2007-021.5 Button: Stanford '51 with ribbons 2007-021.6 Button: Stanford 1951-2001 with 51 in square inside diamond 2007-021.7 Button: I'm Excited! 2007-021.8 Button (rectangle): COMMITTEE 2007-021.9 Red feather 2007-021.10 Class of '51 address stamps (Bowman House) - 2 items 2007-021.11 Reunion ID for Joe Cusick 2001 2007-021.12 Reunion ID for Kathy Cusick 2001 2007-021.13 Reunion ID for Joe Cusick 2006 (with 2 pins) 2007-021.14 Paper flag of Mexico 2007-021.15 Reunion ID for Joe Cusick 1996 2007-021.16 Reunion ID for Joe Cusick (35th) 1986 2007-021.17 Reunion (25th) Committee ribbons
  - Memorabilia: leather bookmark [triangular with U seal] and wooden box for Wilson's chocolates [Wilson's Choclat Chunks. The Candy with a College Education. with image of front of Quad], ARCH-AM-2008-009 (Box 1)
    2008-009.1 leather bookmark 2008-009.2 Wilson's wooden box
  - Memorabilia: t-shirts, banners, sign, ARCH-AM-1985-09 (Box 1)
    1. T-shirt: "Gay and Lesbian Awareness Week. GLAS of Stanford 1985": purple, sleeveless 2. T-shirt: "Gay and Lesbian Awareness Week. GLAS of Stanford 1985": purple, sleeveless 3. T-shirt: "Gay and Lesbian Awareness Week. GLAS of Stanford 1985": maroon 4. Banner: "Dykes Fix Stanford" (Hoover Tower Protest Rally, 1983) 5. Banner: "Gay and Lesbian Awareness Week", ca. 1985 6. Banner: Northern California Gay and Lesbian Students (black with rainbow colors), 1984 7. Sign: "Enter from the Rear" (black and white lettering)
  - Memorial Metal Pillow. 19X23X38 cm. In case. To Mrs. Stanford from locomotive engineers. In memory of Leland Sr., ARCH-AM-00-186 (Box 1)
  - Menu from the dinner given by Mrs. Leland Stanford in Honolulu to resident graduates of LSJU, April 28, 1902 - printed on red silk (3 items), ARCH-AM-2004-021 (Box 1)
  - Menu printed on silk from dinner at Union League Club, April 21, 1883. Menu is on larger banner with 'Hon. Leland Stanford" written on botton portion, ARCH-AM-2004-019 (Box 1)
  - Messonier oil studies (3), ARCH-AM-1981-09 (Box 1)
  - metal and procelain wreaths from the Mausoleum, ARCH-AM-1998-013 (Box 1)
    013.1 cross with flowers (smaller) 013.2 cross with flowers (larger) 013.3 round wreath with flowers 013.4 oval wreath, leaves only 013.5 wooden cross, no flowers or decoration; envelope with loose pieces
  - Metal Cable, 1" section (copper), ARCH-AM-1985-10 (Box 1)
  - Metal cup, 8.4 cm high, "Souvenir of Stanford University" with images of outer quadrangle, Memorial Church, Memorial Arch, quadrangle from arcade, Palo Alto tree. On underside: made in Germany for H. W. Simkins, Palo Alto, Calif., ARCH-AM-1999-016 (Box 1)
  - Metal lath for plaster walls in Main Quad and assumed original light fixture taken from arcade, ARCH-AM-2005-033 (Box 1)
  - Metal letters "H-E-N-R-Y" from J. Henry Meyer Memorial Library, circa 1965-1966; ARCH-AM-2017-019 (Box 1)
  - metal mold for making glass globes used in Quad Arcades, ARCH-AM-2000-040 (Box 1)
  - Metal mold used to produce glass shades for replica lamps in Bldg. 30 (replica of 1890's lights used in quad bldgs). Very heavy item, ARCH-AM-1997-002 (Box 1)
  - Metal part for the Albion printing press, circa 1860; ARCH-AM-2009-037 (Box 1)
  - Metal plaque mounted on wooden shield, 41X42 cm. Stanford shield., ARCH-AM-00-149 (Box 1)
  - metal plaque of the Stanford Flying Club [exact usage unknown]: university seal (with German motto) with Flying Club logo over the tree, ARCH-AM-2002-38 (Box 1)
  - Metal plaque: Dohrmann Grove / In Memory of Emilie Elizabeth Dohrmann / 1879-1966, ARCH-AM-2001-21 (Box 1)
  - Metal plaque: univ. seal (Die Luft) made to be mounted (on wall?), ARCH-AM-1980-14 (Box 1)
  - Metal sign, red, with STANFORD in white letters and L'il Injun head, ARCH-AM-2000-002 (Box 1)
  - Metal Sign: "David Starr Jordan reading address. Dedication of SU", 1891 Oct 1; ARCH-AM-00-158 (Box 1)
  - Metal Sign. 18X5 cm. "Martin Kellogg, Pres. State University reading address. Dedication of SU.", 1891 Oct 1; ARCH-AM-00-156 (Box 1)
  - Metal Sign. 5X20 cm. "Judge James M. McShafter reading address, Dedication of SU.", 1891 Oct 1; ARCH-AM-00-157 (Box 1)
  - Metal tools (3) used in constructing Quad balusters 2002 (or 2001?), ARCH-AM-2002-29 (Box 1)
    Box 1 contains 2 tools (rectangular ones); Box 2 contains 1 tool (curved edge one)
  - Metal version of seal (presidential?) used in commencement activities; made by company that did new commencement stage (2000), ARCH-AM-2000-023 (Box 1)
  - Model - Demolished Encina Gym, ca. 2003 (includes Bakewell Building which was not demolished), ARCH-AM-2005-032 (Box 1)
  - Model - Demolished Stanford Stadium, before 2005; Accession ARCH-AM-2018-005 (Box 1)
  - Monogramed silver coffee pot (8.75" tall) and tray (14" diameter). Both have stamp on bottom of "G M Co" with symbol of an anchor in a shield, ARCH-AM-1998-014 (Box 1)
    98-014.1 coffee pot 98-014.2 tray
    - Mortarboard, Accession ARCH-2018-012
      Cap belonged to Richard Hugo Gatchell, AB History 1948
  - Mortarboard with 2 "78" tassels, 1978; Accession ARCH-AM-2017-005 (Box 1)
  - Mortarboards (1 black, 1 grey) with note, circa 1894; ARCH-AM-00-057 (Box 1)
    Grey mortar board Black mortar board; initials E.B.M. on inside of cap
  - Mosaic chunks from Memorial Church, 1906 Printing plates for Memorial Church, ARCH-AM-1991-098 (Box 1)
  - Mosaic piece from rubble of Memorial Church after the 1906 earthquake - half in blue pieces; other half is part of a red circle with green interior and gold background [6.5 in. point to point], ARCH-AM-2005-042
  - Mosaic piece from Memorial Church, after 1906 earthquake damage [8 x 6 in.; design includes gold half-circle with blue interior from which lines of blue, gold, red and green pieces radiate; below the half-circle are red, white, and brown pieces], ARCH-AM-00-046 (Box 1)
  - Mosaic piece from Memorial Church, gold bkg. 25x53x2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-316 (Box 1)
  - Mosaic pieces from rubble of Memorial Church after the 1906 earthquake, ARCH-AM.2013-002; 2 item(s); (1 box) (Box 1)
  - nail taken from Bldg 1 in the Quad when the entry way was remodeled (ca. 1975). Nail is square and 2.5 inches long; note by Royden included., ARCH-AM-1998-010 (Box 1)
  - nail, old, iron 4 X 2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-144 (Box 1)
  - Nail: old iron, 15 X 2 cm., ARCH-AM-00-143 (Box 1)
  - Name plate for Henry J. Adams Jr. '30. Found on back of a junked chair, in the 1960s., ARCH-AM-2003-013 (Box 1)
  - Name tags, class of '62 reunion. white with red logo., ARCH-AM-1984-39 (Box 1)
  - Napkin, "Stanford 1891-1941": occasion unknown, ARCH-AM-1994-14 (Box 1)
  - Necktie, Stanford Indian, Accession ARCH-AM-2018-009 (Box 1)
    Stanford Indian hand painted in white on red necktie.
  - New Student Orientation button: "Welcome! Stanford 2000", ARCH-AM-2000-024 (Box 1)
    5 copies of one button
  - Number skipped. No item with this number., ARCH-AM-00-130.09 (Box 1)
  - Object of wood, 25cm long, fish & hads(?) carved on bottom (DSJ related?), ARCH-AM-00-147 (Box 1)
  - Oil colored photographs of Memorial Church interior; Bear Photo No. 904 and 910, framed [image post-1906 but items bears no date], ARCH-AM-2005-045 (Box 1)
    2005-045.1 No. 910 Interior of Church 2005-045.2 No. 904 Facade of Church thru arcade arch
  - Oil painting (20x26 in.) possibly of child; very dirty and stained, ARCH-AM-2008-016 (Box 1)
  - Oil painting of Felix Bloch by Daniel Mendelowitz (framed), 1946; ARCH-AM-2010-002 (Box 1)
  - Oil painting of Wilred H. Stone by Daniel Mendelowitz, 1963; framed. See collection file for more information on creation of the painting., ARCH-AM-2000-035 (Box 1)
  - oil painting on canvas, probably of Mary Yost (n.d.) 16 x 21 inches; unframed, ARCH-AM-1998-009 (Box 1)
  - Oil painting, sailing ship, painted by Leland Jr., ARCH-AM-00-072 (Box 1)
  - Oil Painting, Stanford's Residences east and west. 29x46 cm., ARCH-AM-00-100 (Box 1)
  - Oil Painting: 53x67 cm. of man with mustache, Artist's initials; B.H.W.,S/F/gold frame; 91x79 cm., ARCH-AM-00-077 (Box 1)
  - Oil Painting: 66x53, portrait of woman signed; Duesbury Wolfe, gold frame - 91x79 cm, ARCH-AM-00-076 (Box 1)
  - Oil portrait of J. E. W. Sterling, ARCH-AM-2004-007 (Box 1)
  - Oil Portrait, Thomas S. Barclay., ARCH-AM-00-334 (Box 1)
  - Oil sketch for final presidential portrait of R. W. Lyman, ARCH-AM-2003-007 (Box 1)
  - Oil Sketch, Jordon, David Starr by Xavier Martinez 1917. o.d. 53x46 cm., ARCH-AM-00-079 (Box 1)
  - On the President's Review of the War-Fleets peacefully anchored in New York Harbour, April 27th, 1893 - poem by Patrick M. King, printed on silk, ARCH-AM-2004-018 (Box 1)
  - One of original 12 Board of Trustees chairs - wooden, high back, leather upholstered., ARCH-AM-1997-015 (Box 1)
  - One pair of plaster hands, casted, of David Starr Jordan, ARCH-AM-00-001 (Box 1)
  - One pin, one ring, and miniature mallet, ARCH-AM-00-041 (Box 1)
    041.1 broken rifle pin 041.2 ring with hand in peace sign (damaged) 041.3 miniature mallet
  - Opera glasses holder (?), ARCH-AM-1992-07 (Box 1)
  - Order of the Baluster presented to Jim Triolo July 2, 1960 [An original stair baluster from Encina with 4 text plaques attached, one of which lists his colleagues - Lyle Cook, Ken Cuthbertson, Dave Jacobxon, Daryl Pearson, Joe Ruetz and others], ARCH-AM-2006-025 (Box 1)
  - Orientation buttons (6 copies) - "Welcome! 2001 Stanford Orientation", ARCH-AM-2001-19 (Box 1)
  - Orientation buttons 2007 [no date on button]: I [heart] Freshmen; I [heart] Transfers; and I [heart] Freshmen & Transfers (7 buttons in all), ARCH-AM-2008-005 (Box 1)
  - Orientation buttons, 1995-1998; ARCH-AM-1998-016 (Box 1)
    016.1 "Welcome" 1995 016.2 "Stanford Welcomes You!" 1996 016.3 "Welcome! Stanford Orientation 1997" 016.4 "Welcome! Stanford Orientation 1997" 016.5 "Welcome! Stanford Orientation 1997" 016.6 "Welcome to STANFORD! 1998 Orientation" 016.7 "Welcome to STANFORD! 1998 Orientation" 016.8 "Welcome to STANFORD! 1998 Orientation"
  - Orientation gift box labeled "good stuff The Student Sampler" with "female" in the lower right corner - contained toiletries, laundry soap, etc. (1977), ARCH-AM-2001-16 (Box 1)
  - Original bindings for 2 volumes of the Jane L. Stanford letters [letters removed 1998], no date; ARCH-AM-2009-009 (Box 1)
  - Original copper box used for the time capsule buried in building 160 in 1898., ARCH-AM-2002-027 (Box 1)
  - Original gas valve from boiler at Meyer Buck estate (failed and removed in 1982), ARCH-AM-1997-025 (Box 1)
  - Original linoleum flooring in dorm rooms, Toyon Hall, ARCH-AM-2002-03 (Box 1)
  - Original mortar from Quad balusters and balustrade (no date given), undated; ARCH-AM-2009-023 (Box 1)
    1 envelope of mortar pieces
  - Original stair balusters from Encina (blown out by the fire-hose prank) that were used as "Order of the Baluster" awards to fund-raisers, ARCH-AM-2001-35 (Box 1)
    35.1 awarded to Charles W. Getchell, Jr., 1959 Stanford Fund 35.2 awarded to Charles W. Getchell, Jr., 1961 Stanford Fund 35.3 awarded to Joseph D. Cusick, 1963/64 Stanford Fund 35.4 awarded to Joseph D. Cusick, 1964/65 Stanford Fund
  - Original Stanford colors, framed., ARCH-AM-00-351 (Box 1)
  - Originally: Assorted items (hats, cans, papers) found under the Drell House and others that were moved in the Spring of 2006 (to make way for the Munger dorms), ARCH-AM-2006-015 (Box 1)
    Items retained: 2 wooden hangers from PA cleaners; bills, checks, and photos of Daniel Drell; Ruth Sterne's German I test; 2 letters and 1 card
  - Ornate Gold Frame, o.d. 96x86 cm., red velvet mount (no picture), ARCH-AM-00-087 (Box 1)
  - OS reproductions of images of the frieze from the Memorial Arch used in a mock-up of the Arch created in the Art Dept. (5 boards), ARCH-AM-2006-011 (Box 1)
  - OSOC tshirt ("Who runs Stanford?" "WE DO! OSOC" and buttons, red letters on white: O S O C, ARCH-AM-1981-13 (Box 1)
    81-13.1 tshirt 81-13.2 Lapel button (5)
  - Oxford Hood and mortor board of Dr. Charles Gardner, chaplain, ARCH-AM-1983-10 (Box 1)
  - Paddle board, ARCH-AM-00-031 (Box 1)